<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PHP | Difio]]></title>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/categories/php/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-22T14:11:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://dif.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Difio Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio 1.5 Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/06/04/difio-1.5-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-04T13:24:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/06/04/difio-1.5-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce version 1.5
of our updates monitoring service. Difio provides insight of available
updates for open source components. It lets you inspect changes and take
informed decision when or what to upgrade. This improves software life cycle
planning and minimizes possible regressions and downtime.</p>

<p>This release adds support for <a href="http://pear.php.net/">PHP PEAR</a> packages and
new registration agents for <a href="http://dotcloud.com">dotCloud</a> and
<a href="http://openshift.redhat.com">OpenShift</a> PHP applications. See
<a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">how to register applications</a> page for more information.
Currently only packages from <a href="http://pear.php.net">http://pear.php.net</a> channel are supported.
We're working on enabling additional channels like <a href="http://pecl.php.net">PECL</a>
and self hosted PEAR channels.</p>

<p>In addition to popular package index directories there are many projects which
are distributed directly and not via package index. We've made a first step towards
supporting such projects. This release adds support for projects which are
distributed directly from <a href="http://github.com">GitHub</a>. At the moment support is limited
to projects which use tags.</p>

<p>Our web site now supports search functionality via Google custom search.</p>

<p>In the next releases we're going to add registration agents for more cloud/PaaS vendors
and enable manual import of packages for those who do not work in the clouds. Our team
is working on a number of website improvements to make it faster and easier to use.
In addition to that we're also working on enabling e-mail and SMS notifications so
stay tuned!</p>

<p><a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/applications/mine/">Give it a try</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">follow us</a> on Twitter for more news.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
