<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[monupco]]></title>
  <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-01T22:39:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://monupco.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Monupco Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FAQ]]></title>
    <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/2012/01/30/faq/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T21:11:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://monupco.com/blog/2012/01/30/faq</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>What is this</h2>

<p>Monupco is a service which let&#8217;s you know what package updates are available
for your applications deployed in the cloud. We try to provide meaningful and
accurate information whenever possible by monitoring various sources of information.</p>

<h2>Why should I care <!--more --></h2>

<p>In a cloud environment you care about your own code and leave updates to the vendor.
However applications install 3rd party dependencies which are not part of the vendor platform.
These packages may present security vulnerabilities or incompatibilities and disruption of service
if left unmaintained. This is why Monupco exists.</p>

<h2>How much does it cost</h2>

<p>The service will remain free of charge during Alpha and Beta versions.
We may need to charge a small ammount afterwards.
Don&#8217;t worry it will not be more than a few bucks.</p>

<h2>How to install</h2>

<p>The client side code for Monupco is open source and is split into
different packages depending on cloud vendor and framework type.
For detailed install instructions see the README files in
our GitHub repositories at <a href="https://github.com/monupco">https://github.com/monupco</a>.</p>

<h2>Why do I need to approve applications</h2>

<p>Applications are registered on behalf of your username only because
we don&#8217;t want you to accidentally commit the password in your source code.
To ensure that you registered the application it has to be approved first.
This is similar to the account approval process on some websites.</p>

<h2>When is application data updated</h2>

<p>Data for packages installed on your applications is tipically updated when you
push a new version of the application which may pull in new dependencies for example.</p>

<h2>Why some updates do not show immediately</h2>

<p>New versions are added periodically by an automated process.
Data is then reviewed and scrutinized by a human to ensure it is correct.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
