<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: API | Difio]]></title>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/categories/api/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-05T14:53:43+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://dif.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Difio Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio 1.9 Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/14/difio-1.9-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T10:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/14/difio-1.9-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce version 1.9
of our dependencies monitoring service. Difio keeps track of application
dependencies and tells you when they change. We let you inspect the
changes and make informed decision when or what to upgrade.</p>

<p>This release includes several new features and website updates.</p>

<h2>API diff</h2>

<p>The <em>API diff</em> feature is exploring packages source code and builds their
API definitions. Then definitions between your currently installed package
and the latest upstream version are compared. Changes are presented as a
colored diff format for better readability.</p>

<p><em>API diff</em> is accessible through the main update view, next to changelog,
commit log and bugs list as shown below:</p>

<p><img src="/images/api_diff.png" title="API diff example" alt="API diff example" /></p>

<p><em>API diff</em> is initially available only for Python. For Python we support
detection of class definitions, function definitions and decorators.</p>

<p>Example showing no API changes can be seen with a recent
<a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/MySQL-python-1.2.4b5/MySQL-python-1.2.4c1/8439/">MySQL-python release</a>.</p>

<p>Example showing new classes being added and some functions changing can be
seen with a recent
<a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/django-social-auth-0.7.7/django-social-auth-0.7.9/8791/">django-social-auth release</a>.</p>

<p><em>API diff</em> support for other languages will be added in future releases!</p>

<h2>Refresh manually imported apps</h2>

<p>It is now possible to refresh the dependency list for manually imported applications.
Simply click the <em>Refresh</em> button as shown below and import the dependency list again.</p>

<p><img src="/images/refresh_app.png" title="Refresh button" alt="Refresh button" /></p>

<p>The refresh functionality has always been present for all of our PaaS
<a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">registration agents</a>.</p>

<h2>Share the package list</h2>

<p>When you need to match your dev environment with the production one, or
ensure dependency similarity between multiple nodes you need the
list of already installed packages.</p>

<p>In this release Difio adds a new button labeled <em>Package List</em> which exports
all installed dependencies as plain text. The format is name==version.
You can share this list with other developers as needed.</p>

<h2>Minor improvements and bug fixes</h2>

<p>We have also done lots of minor improvements and fixes to our website.
They are invisible to the naked eye so no need to tell you more :).</p>

<p>We encourage developers from all backgrounds and languages to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a>
their applications and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
