<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Perl | Difio]]></title>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/categories/perl/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-25T12:33:08+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://dif.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Difio Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio 1.6 Public Beta Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/07/11/difio-1.6-public-beta-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T13:34:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/07/11/difio-1.6-public-beta-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce version 1.6
of our updates monitoring service. Difio provides insight of available
updates for open source components. It lets you inspect changes and take
informed decision when or what to upgrade. This improves software life cycle
planning and minimizes possible regressions and downtime.</p>

<p>This release inludes tons of bug fixes and improvements to the service.
Suport for manually importing packages is available as well. If you are not
able to install any of our registration agents you can manually import a list
of name/version pairs and follow updates for them. This functionality is available
for Python, Ruby, Perl and Node.js environments. See
<a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">how to register applications</a> page for more information.</p>

<p>With this release Difio enters Public Beta and registration is open to everyone.
We encourage developers of all backgrounds to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a>
their applications and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/applications/mine/">Give it a try</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio 1.3 Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/04/02/difio-1.3-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-02T10:17:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/04/02/difio-1.3-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce version 1.3
of our updates monitoring service. Difio provides user friendly interface to
monitor available updates for your cloud applications and information about different
package versions.</p>

<p>This release adds support for Perl packages from <a href="http://search.cpan.org/">CPAN</a>.
Request Tracker issue tracking systems on <a href="http://rt.cpan.org">http://rt.cpan.org</a> and <a href="http://rt.perl.org">http://rt.perl.org</a>
are also supported.</p>

<p>Perl support comes with registration agents for <a href="http://dotcloud.com">dotCloud</a> and
<a href="http://openshift.redhat.com">OpenShift</a>. See the
<a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">how to register applications</a> page for more information.</p>

<p>Our web interface faced some changes too:</p>

<ul>
<li>Details about changes is no longer processed as Markdown. It is presented as
pre-formatted plain text. This is to prevent some characters (like underscores) getting
lost due to Markdown conversion;</li>
<li>Update pages now integrate with <a href="http://disqus.com">Disqus</a>. You can use the comments form
to provide general feedback and comments and to alert our team in case the information
is incorrect.</li>
</ul>


<p>Difio has already produced detailed information for 950+ <a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/updates/">updates</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/applications/mine/" class="button dark_blue small">Give It A Try</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">follow us</a> on Twitter for more news.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
