<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | Monupco]]></title>
  <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-16T22:38:22+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://monupco.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Monupco Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monupco 1.2 Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/2012/02/17/monupco-1.2-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-17T00:34:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://monupco.com/blog/2012/02/17/monupco-1.2-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://monupco.com">Monupco</a> is pleased to announce version 1.2
of our updates monitoring service. Monupco provides user friendly interface to
monitor available updates for your cloud applications and information about different
package versions.</p>

<p>This release adds support for <a href="http://npmjs.org">NodeJS</a> packages. We've
aready imported 1000 of the most dependent upon packages and started to process updates.
Monupco has already produced detailed information for 60+ <a href="http://monupco.com/advisories/">advisories</a>.</p>

<p>Client side registration tool for NodeJS applications hosted at <a href="http://dotcloud.com">dotCloud</a> has
been added as well. It is contributed and maintained by <a href="http://github.com/zaro">Svetlozar Argirov</a>.
For more information see the <a href="http://monupco.com/install">install</a> page.</p>

<p>Small improvements to the web interface were made:</p>

<ul>
<li>Added pagination to the advisories and application details pages;</li>
<li>Added buttons to show only packages which need updates in application details page;</li>
<li>Added buttons to filter applications by status.</li>
</ul>


<p>In the next weeks we're looking to enable support for Ruby, PHP, Perl and Java and extend
client side tools to more vendors. Stay <a href="https://twitter.com/monupco">tuned</a> if you don't
want to miss the announcement.</p>

<p><a href="https://monupco-otb.rhcloud.com/applications/mine/" class="button red small"><span>Give It A Try Now</span></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monupco 1.1 Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://monupco.com/blog/2012/02/06/monupco-1.1-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T10:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://monupco.com/blog/2012/02/06/monupco-1.1-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://monupco.com">Monupco</a> is pleased to announce the general availability
of our updates monitoring service. Monupco provides user friendly interface to
monitor available updates for your cloud applications and information about different
package versions.</p>

<p>This is an alpha release for early adopters. Currently we support registration of
Python applications hosted on Red Hat's <a href="http://openshift.redhat.com">OpenShift Express</a>
platform. Client side tools and installation information can be found at our
<a href="https://github.com/monupco/monupco-openshift-express-python">GitHub page</a>.</p>

<p>Monupco itself is developed in the cloud, for the cloud. We're working to support
additional cloud vendors and more programming languages. Your feedback is valuable to us!
We welcome your feature requests on <a href="http://twitter.com/monupco">Twitter</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/monupco/monupco.github.com/issues/new">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>Monupco will remain free of charge until it reaches production-ready quality, when
subscription plans will be announced. A gratis period and/or bonus credits will be made
available to all early birds at that time.</p>

<p>We provide simplified registration and log in into our management console using
credentials from popular social networking providers.</p>

<p><a href="https://monupco-otb.rhcloud.com/applications/mine/" class="button red small"><span>Give It A Try Now</span></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
