<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | Difio]]></title>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-08T00:30:29+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://dif.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Difio Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio Add-On Tests Are Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/05/07/difio-add-on-tests-available/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-07T15:03:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/05/07/difio-add-on-tests-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce the general
availability of <a href="http://www.dif.io/add-on/">add-on tests</a> which are
designed to test and verify potential issues or
known bugs. Add-on tests are provided as a
<a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/profiles/mine/">subscription service</a>
for 10 $ per month. First month is free.</p>

<h2>What add-on tests are available</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>API diff</strong> - Difio generates API definition from the package
source code. Changes in API could be
backward incompatible and result in application crash and runtime failures.
API diff is currently available for <strong>Python</strong>, <strong>PHP</strong> and <strong>Java</strong>.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Full diff</strong> - this is the full git diff between two package versions.
It is available for informational purposes.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Package Size Change</strong> - packages that change their size significantly
can be a sign of
a <a href="https://github.com/tschellenbach/Django-facebook/issues/262">corrupted build</a>.
This test reports any size changes over 30%.
See <a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/django-facebook-4.2.11/django-facebook-4.3.0/12243/">DIFIO-12243</a> for example.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>File Size Change</strong> - inspects files which are present in both versions.
Any size change that is both more than 20% and more than 20 KB or
any file that changes from being zero-sized to non-zero sized, and vice-versa is reported.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Added non-text Files</strong> - new files are classified with libmagic.
Any non-text file is reported.
Bugs like <a href="https://code.djangoproject.com/ticket/19858">Django #19858</a> can
be found with this test. For example see <a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/Django-1.4.3/Django-1.4.4/12987/">DIFIO-12987</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Modified Files</strong> - lists all modified files. You should manually review the
list and inspect if unwanted files were modified.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Added Files</strong> - lists all newly added files. New files are usually resources, tests of new
functionality. Manually inspect to verify additions are expected.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Removed Files</strong> - files in packages should be removed only if properly obsoleted or
initial inclusion was a bug. Removing modules or parts of them can break the API.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Renamed Files</strong> - renaming files can break API. This test lists all renames
between two versions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Permissions Change</strong> - file permissions change (Linux/UNIX only) could indicate
security issues. In a source package without executable programs permissions should
not change.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Symlinks</strong> - this test traverses the entire package tree and reports any symlinks found.
It will report FAIL if any symlinks exist in the new package.
For example see <a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/factory_boy-1.2.0/factory_boy-2.0.0/16005/">DIFIO-16005</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>File Types Change</strong> - this test compares file types reported by libmagic between
two package versions. Files should not be changing their type between updates.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Virus Scan</strong> - a virus scan is performed on the package using the ClamAV virus scanner.
Even though it is unlikely that packages contain viruses, it's still important to know if anti
virus tools will trigger false positives.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Test Cases</strong> - this test reports any changes in test cases. It counts the number of available
test case files in some well known locations. If new version is missing tests or has less
then severity will be VERIFY or FAIL.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/profiles/mine/" class="button medium dark_blue">Subscribe Now!</a></p>

<hr />

<p>Difio is constantly working on improving the service. In the mean time
<a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/dashboard/follow/">start following packages</a>,
invite your friends and send us your feedback via
<a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[API diff Support for Java and PHP]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/03/10/api-diff-support-for-java-and-php/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T21:55:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/03/10/api-diff-support-for-java-and-php</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce API diff support
for Java and PHP programming languages.</p>

<p>The API diff feature extracts class and method signatures and compares the
results between an older and a newer version. If API has changed this
is a good indicator that there were substantial changes in the new package
version, which require through testing.</p>

<p>With this release API diff becomes available for source code written in
Java, PHP and Python. We are looking to support other languages as well.</p>

<h2>What's next</h2>

<p>Difio is constantly working on improving the service. In the mean time
<a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/dashboard/follow/">start following packages</a>,
invite your friends and send us your feedback via
<a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Support for PHP]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/03/06/improved-support-for-php/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-06T11:05:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/03/06/improved-support-for-php</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce improved support
for the PHP programming language and the
<a href="http://getcomposer.org">Composer</a> dependency management tool.</p>

<p>Previously only PHP PEAR packages were supported and it was not possible
to manually import a list of packages. Starting today, these issues have been
fixed.</p>

<p>At the moment Difio supports three upstream sources for PHP packages:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://packagist.org/">https://packagist.org/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pear.php.net/">http://pear.php.net/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pear2.php.net/">http://pear2.php.net/</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Users are now able to manually import package list from their PHP applications
using Composer.</p>

<p>To register PHP apps go to
<a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/application/import/composer-show/?">https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/application/import/composer-show/?</a>
and paste the output of <code>php composer.phar show --installed</code> command.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<pre><code>$ ./composer.phar show --installed
doctrine/common                              2.3.0   Common Library for Doctrine projects
imagine/Imagine                              v0.4.1  Image processing for PHP 5.3
pear-pear.php.net/HTTP_Request2              2.1.1   PHP5 rewrite of HTTP_Request package ...
pear-pear.php.net/XML_Util                   1.2.1   Selection of methods that are often needed when working with XML documents ...
pear-pear2.php.net/PEAR2_Cache_SHM           0.1.0   Allows you to share data across requests as long as the PHP process is running. ...
pear-pear2.php.net/PEAR2_Text_Markdown       0.1.0   This is a port of Solar_Markdown.
psr/log                                      1.0.0   Common interface for logging libraries
symfony/symfony                              v2.2.0  The Symfony PHP framework
twig/twig                                    v1.12.2 Twig, the flexible, fast, and secure template language for PHP
</code></pre>

<p>This application contains packages from the three different sources and they
will be properly parsed and recognized by Difio.</p>

<h2>What's next</h2>

<p>Difio is constantly working on improving the service. We are now looking into
API diff support for PHP among other things, so stay tuned!
In the mean time
<a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/dashboard/follow/">start following packages</a>,
invite your friends and send us your feedback via
<a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Dashboard and Follow Packages Functionality]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/25/new-dashboard-and-follow-packages/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-25T11:55:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/25/new-dashboard-and-follow-packages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce our new dashboard
and the ability to follow packages without registering applications. Read
below for more information.</p>

<p><strong>Latest Releases</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/new_dashboard/releases.png" title="Latest Releases" alt="Latest Releases" /></p>

<p>The default dashboard page is showing a news stream of all latest releases
for packages the user is following or using inside applications.</p>

<p><strong>Change History</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/new_dashboard/change_history.png" title="Change History" alt="Change History" /></p>

<p>This page is showing a news stream of change analysis between multiple package
versions that the user is following or using inside applications. As shown in this
example the user is following <code>bundler-1.2.1</code> and <code>bundler-1.2.3</code> while the latest
available is <code>bundler-1.3.0</code> and <code>bundler-1.2.5</code>.</p>

<p><strong>Follow Packages</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/new_dashboard/follow.png" title="Follow Packages" alt="Follow Packages" /></p>

<p>A new page to view and search packages is now available. Users can follow or unfollow
any packages and versions they want through the buttons. Simple color codes
distinguish between different states: green - user is following version;
gray - version is used inside registered application; transparent - not following version.
Versions which are used inside applications can only be removed/unfollowed by deleting
the entire application, or deleting the package from the application.
For example <code>Pygments-1.5</code> is been used in an application, but <code>Pygments-1.6</code> is been
followed manually.</p>

<p>It is highly recommended to follow a particular version, not only the package name.
If a user decides to follow only package name, but not versions, Difio will not be
able to generate change analysis reports because there's no
basis to compare to. In this case the user will be able to see only the latest
releases news stream.</p>

<p><strong>Applications</strong></p>

<p>This page is showing all registered applications for which Difio is monitoring dependencies.
This page has been available previously and also includes the improvements
<a href="/blog/2013/02/21/new-look-feel-application-info-pages/">announced last week</a>.
Small speed improvements have been made to this page as well.</p>

<p><strong>Invite Friends</strong></p>

<p>This is an interactive dialog which allows you to invite your fellows to try Difio.
It only asks for the email addresses of your friends and sends them an invitation.
We do not keep track of these addresses nor send any spam to them.</p>

<hr />

<p>We encourage developers from all supported backgrounds and
languages to <a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/dashboard/follow/">start following packages</a>
and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Look and Feel for Application Info Pages]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/21/new-look-feel-application-info-pages/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-21T00:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/21/new-look-feel-application-info-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce new look and feel
for application info pages. Difio keeps track of application
dependencies and tells you when they change. We let you inspect the
changes and make informed decision when or what to upgrade.</p>

<p><img src="/images/new_app_info.png" title="App Info page" alt="App Info Page" /></p>

<p>Previously the application info page was showing only the latest available
updates. This made it hard for users to inspect older updates.
For example if you had Django-1.4.3 you would see the
latest Django-1.4.5 but not 1.4.4.</p>

<p>For packages which maintain several active branches it was not possible to
compare installed version against stable branch versions. It was always compared
to the latest from the master branch.
For example if you had ffi-1.3.0 you could not see ffi-1.3.1 but
would see ffi-1.4.0 instead.</p>

<p>Today's release fixes this by offering the user all available updates to
their packages. In addition change rate icons are replaced by color codes.
The version string is now shown as a button in one of the standard colors
green (low), orange (medium) or red (high). Improvement has been made to
the page load speed as well. It is now significantly faster.</p>

<p>Email notifications still display only the highest available version.
This will be changed soon to include intermediate versions.
At the moment information about intermediate versions is available only
via the web interface or <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/difio/updates">RSS</a>.</p>

<p>We encourage developers from all backgrounds and
languages to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a> their applications and
send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
