<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | Difio]]></title>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dif.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-25T12:33:08+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://dif.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Difio Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Dashboard and Follow Packages Functionality]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/25/new-dashboard-and-follow-packages/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-25T11:55:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/25/new-dashboard-and-follow-packages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce our new dashboard
and the ability to follow packages without registering applications. Read
below for more information.</p>

<p><strong>Latest Releases</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/new_dashboard/releases.png" title="Latest Releases" alt="Latest Releases" /></p>

<p>The default dashboard page is showing a news stream of all latest releases
for packages the user is following or using inside applications.</p>

<p><strong>Change History</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/new_dashboard/change_history.png" title="Change History" alt="Change History" /></p>

<p>This page is showing a news stream of change analysis between multiple package
versions that the user is following or using inside applications. As shown in this
example the user is following <code>bundler-1.2.1</code> and <code>bundler-1.2.3</code> while the latest
available is <code>bundler-1.3.0</code> and <code>bundler-1.2.5</code>.</p>

<p><strong>Follow Packages</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/new_dashboard/follow.png" title="Follow Packages" alt="Follow Packages" /></p>

<p>A new page to view and search packages is now available. Users can follow or unfollow
any packages and versions they want through the buttons. Simple color codes
distinguish between different states: green - user is following version;
gray - version is used inside registered application; transparent - not following version.
Versions which are used inside applications can only be removed/unfollowed by deleting
the entire application, or deleting the package from the application.
For example <code>Pygments-1.5</code> is been used in an application, but <code>Pygments-1.6</code> is been
followed manually.</p>

<p>It is highly recommended to follow a particular version, not only the package name.
If a user decides to follow only package name, but not versions, Difio will not be
able to generate change analysis reports because there's no
basis to compare to. In this case the user will be able to see only the latest
releases news stream.</p>

<p><strong>Applications</strong></p>

<p>This page is showing all registered applications for which Difio is monitoring dependencies.
This page has been available previously and also includes the improvements
<a href="/blog/2013/02/21/new-look-feel-application-info-pages/">announced last week</a>.
Small speed improvements have been made to this page as well.</p>

<p><strong>Invite Friends</strong></p>

<p>This is an interactive dialog which allows you to invite your fellows to try Difio.
It only asks for the email addresses of your friends and sends them an invitation.
We do not keep track of these addresses nor send any spam to them.</p>

<hr />

<p>We encourage developers from all supported backgrounds and
languages to <a href="https://difio-otb.rhcloud.com/dashboard/follow/">start following packages</a>
and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Look and Feel for Application Info Pages]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/21/new-look-feel-application-info-pages/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-21T00:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2013/02/21/new-look-feel-application-info-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce new look and feel
for application info pages. Difio keeps track of application
dependencies and tells you when they change. We let you inspect the
changes and make informed decision when or what to upgrade.</p>

<p><img src="/images/new_app_info.png" title="App Info page" alt="App Info Page" /></p>

<p>Previously the application info page was showing only the latest available
updates. This made it hard for users to inspect older updates.
For example if you had Django-1.4.3 you would see the
latest Django-1.4.5 but not 1.4.4.</p>

<p>For packages which maintain several active branches it was not possible to
compare installed version against stable branch versions. It was always compared
to the latest from the master branch.
For example if you had ffi-1.3.0 you could not see ffi-1.3.1 but
would see ffi-1.4.0 instead.</p>

<p>Today's release fixes this by offering the user all available updates to
their packages. In addition change rate icons are replaced by color codes.
The version string is now shown as a button in one of the standard colors
green (low), orange (medium) or red (high). Improvement has been made to
the page load speed as well. It is now significantly faster.</p>

<p>Email notifications still display only the highest available version.
This will be changed soon to include intermediate versions.
At the moment information about intermediate versions is available only
via the web interface or <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/difio/updates">RSS</a>.</p>

<p>We encourage developers from all backgrounds and
languages to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a> their applications and
send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio Adds Application History Tracking]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/27/difio-adds-application-history-tracking/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T23:04:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/27/difio-adds-application-history-tracking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce
support for tracking application history. Difio keeps track of application
dependencies and tells you when they change. We let you inspect the
changes and make informed decision when or what to upgrade.</p>

<p>Our team has added a new feature to track changes in the list of
dependencies used by applications. Every time you upgrade, add or remove a
package from your application dependencies Difio creates a history record.
As always, don't forget to re-run the registration script or to manually refresh
your apps after changing the dependencies!</p>

<p>Every application starts with a single history record, reflecting its latest state.
Later you can review your app history and revert to previously used versions
for example. Difio is planning to add more goodies to the history page in a future
release. If you have an idea and want us to implement it, please post it on the
<a href="http://www.dif.io/#ideas">ideas dashboard</a>!</p>

<p>This new functionality is accessible on the application details view via the
<em>Last check-in</em> hyperlink, as shown below.</p>

<p><img src="/images/apphistory.png" title="Link to history page" alt="Link to history page" /></p>

<p>We encourage developers from all backgrounds and languages to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a>
their applications and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio 1.9 Release Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/14/difio-1.9-release-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T10:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/14/difio-1.9-release-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce version 1.9
of our dependencies monitoring service. Difio keeps track of application
dependencies and tells you when they change. We let you inspect the
changes and make informed decision when or what to upgrade.</p>

<p>This release includes several new features and website updates.</p>

<h2>API diff</h2>

<p>The <em>API diff</em> feature is exploring packages source code and builds their
API definitions. Then definitions between your currently installed package
and the latest upstream version are compared. Changes are presented as a
colored diff format for better readability.</p>

<p><em>API diff</em> is accessible through the main update view, next to changelog,
commit log and bugs list as shown below:</p>

<p><img src="/images/api_diff.png" title="API diff example" alt="API diff example" /></p>

<p><em>API diff</em> is initially available only for Python. For Python we support
detection of class definitions, function definitions and decorators.</p>

<p>Example showing no API changes can be seen with a recent
<a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/MySQL-python-1.2.4b5/MySQL-python-1.2.4c1/8439/">MySQL-python release</a>.</p>

<p>Example showing new classes being added and some functions changing can be
seen with a recent
<a href="http://www.dif.io/updates/django-social-auth-0.7.7/django-social-auth-0.7.9/8791/">django-social-auth release</a>.</p>

<p><em>API diff</em> support for other languages will be added in future releases!</p>

<h2>Refresh manually imported apps</h2>

<p>It is now possible to refresh the dependency list for manually imported applications.
Simply click the <em>Refresh</em> button as shown below and import the dependency list again.</p>

<p><img src="/images/refresh_app.png" title="Refresh button" alt="Refresh button" /></p>

<p>The refresh functionality has always been present for all of our PaaS
<a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">registration agents</a>.</p>

<h2>Share the package list</h2>

<p>When you need to match your dev environment with the production one, or
ensure dependency similarity between multiple nodes you need the
list of already installed packages.</p>

<p>In this release Difio adds a new button labeled <em>Package List</em> which exports
all installed dependencies as plain text. The format is name==version.
You can share this list with other developers as needed.</p>

<h2>Minor improvements and bug fixes</h2>

<p>We have also done lots of minor improvements and fixes to our website.
They are invisible to the naked eye so no need to tell you more :).</p>

<p>We encourage developers from all backgrounds and languages to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a>
their applications and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difio Adds Initial Support for cloudControl]]></title>
    <link href="http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/05/difio-adds-initial-support-for-cloudcontrol/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T22:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dif.io/blog/2012/11/05/difio-adds-initial-support-for-cloudcontrol</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://www.dif.io">Difio</a> is pleased to announce initial
support for <a href="http://cloudcontrol.com">cloudControl</a>. Difio provides insight of available
updates for open source components. It lets you inspect changes and take
informed decision when or what to upgrade. This improves software life cycle
planning and minimizes possible regressions and downtime.</p>

<p>We have added two new registration scripts allowing <em>cloudControl</em> developers to
subscribe their applications to Difio. At the moment there is support for
<a href="https://github.com/difio/difio-cloudcontrol-python/blob/master/README.rst">Python</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/difio/difio-cloudcontrol-ruby/blob/master/README.md">Ruby</a>
programming languages. Difio is working together with <em>cloudControl</em> to add support
for Java and PHP as well, so stay tuned!</p>

<p>We encourage developers who use <em>cloudControl</em> to <a href="http://www.dif.io/register/">register</a>
their applications and send us their feedback via <a href="https://github.com/difio/bugs/issues/new">GitHub</a>
or <a href="https://twitter.com/DifioNews">Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
